Finding Aid for D. N. Lowell collection of pamphlets and publications
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
D. N. Lowell collection of pamphlets and publications 1855-1882
Lowell, Dwight Nelson, d. 1907, collector
60 items (in 6 bound volumes) approximate
753 DA 2; L914; P186
University of Michigan graduate, 1867, and lawyer in Macomb County, Michigan. Collection of pamphlets and other printed material relating to history of the university, the legal profession and other matters.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The provenance of this collection is unknown.
No further additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Many of the items are cataloged individually in MIRLYN, the University of Michigan online catalog.
Dwight N. Lowell was a graduate of the University of Michigan (A.B. 1867) and a Macomb County attorney. He was also a collector of pamphlets and other publications primarily relating to the University of Michigan. Lowell died July 27, 1907.
The Lowell pamphlet collection consists of 6 bound volumes of pamphlets and other publications relating primarily to the history of the University of Michigan, including reports and addresses of the presidents, commencement addresses, and reports on misappropriation of funds in the chemistry department; messages and reports of the Michigan governors, and a number of articles on law and the legal profession.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--History--19th century.; University of Michigan. Dept. of Law.; Baccalaureate addresses--University of Michigan.; Education.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
- Pamphlets and publications
  - University of Michigan Thirty-fourth Annual Commencement. [Ann Arbor June 27, 1878 ] (Volume I)
  - Lothrop, George V. N. A Plea for Education as a Public Duty. [Ann Arbor 1878 ]
  - Kent, Charles A. The Work of Lawyers and its Relation to Society. [Ann Arbor 1871 ]
  - Coolidge, Orville William. The Relation of Higher Education to the State. [Ann Arbor 1878 ]
  - Sheldon, Mary D. A Legend of the Amazon; Poem. [Ann Arbor 1878 ]
  - Angell, James B. The President's Report to the Board of Regents. [Ann Arbor 1879 ]
  - Abbott, T. C. Agricultural Education. [Lansing, Michigan 1875 ]
  - Fairfield, Reverend Edmund B. Wickedness in High Places, [2nd edition. Mansfield, Ohio 1874 ]
  - Croswell, Charles M. Message of [Charles M. Croswell] Governor of the State of Michigan to the Legislature, at its 30th Regular Session, January 2, 1879. [Lansing, Michigan 1879 ]
  - Croswell, Charles M. Message of [Charles M.-Croswell] Retiring Governor of Michigan, to the Legislature, January 6, 1881. [Lansing, Michigan 1881 ]
  - Jerome, David H. Special Message of [David H. Jerome] Governor of the State of Michigan to the Legislature, In Extra Session, February 23, 1882, [Lansing, Michigan 1882 ]
  - Jerome, David H. Message of [David H. Jerome] Retiring Governor of Michigan, to the Legislature, January 3, 1883. [Lansing, Michigan 1883 ]
  - Begole, Josiah W. Inaugural Message of [Josiah W. Begole] Governor of the State of Michigan, to the Legislature, January 3, 1883. [Lansing, Michigan 1883 ]
  - Conditions and Needs of Spring Wheat Culture in The Northwest. [n.p., undated]
  - Michigan. Commissioner of Immigration. Michigan and its Resources. [Lansing, Michigan 1882 ]
  - Blaine, James G. Memorial Address on the Life and Character of James Abram Garfield. [Washington, D.C. 1882 ] (Volume II)
  - The Defalcation in the Chemical Laboratory of the University of Michigan. [Ann Arbor 1878 ]
  - Pitcher, Zina. A Memoir Embracing An Epitome of the Transactions of the Regents of the University, with Some Reasons for the Adoption of their More Important Measures, from 1837 to June 30, 1851 ...., [Ann Arbor, Michigan 1851 ]
  - Constitutional Provisions, Laws and By-laws of the University of Michigan, [revised edition. Ann Arbor 1864 ]
  - Opinions of the Judges of the Supreme Court of Michigan, In the Case of the People ex rel. the Detroit and Howell Railroad Company vs. the Township Board of Salem. [Lansing, Michigan 1870 ]
  - Michigan Lawyer. Wit and Wisdom of the Law. [ undated ]
  - Levities of the Law. Michigan Lawyer, [ undated ]
  - Trial by Jury. Michigan Lawyer, [ undated ]
  - Extradition, by T. M. Cooley. Michigan Lawyer, [ undated ]
  - Michigan Lawyer. Impeachment of Secretary Belknap, by Isaac P. Christiancy. Michigan Lawyer, [ undated ]
  - Reports of Selected Cases Decided in the Circuit Courts of Michigan, Fourth Circuit, Circuit Court for Washtenaw County; The Regents of the University of Michigan vs. Silas H. Douglas, Preston B. Rose et al. [ undated ]
  - Dudley, Thomas H., Reply to Augustus Mongredien's Appeal to the Western Farmer of America. [Philadelphia, Pennsylvania 1880 ]
  - Decoration Day. [Detroit May 30, 1879 ]
  - Bours, Allen L. Inaugural Proceedings at the Dedication of the New Capitol of Michigan. [Lansing Michigan 1879 ]
  - Michigan Legislative Excursion. [Lansing, Michigan 1869 ]
  - Wilber, Mark D. Speech in the Senate of Michigan, March 26, 1873 Advocating the Constitution of the Michigan Ship Canal. [Lansing, Michigan 1873 ]
  - Baldwin, Henry P. Biennial Message of Henry P. Baldwin, Governor of the State of Michigan to the Legislature. [Lansing, Michigan 1871 ]
  - Oration July 4 1879.
    [t.p. lacking]
  - Backus, C. K. The Contraction of the Currency. [Chicago, Illinois 1878 ]
  - Perry, (Professor). How Paper Money Cheats Farmers. Omaha, Nebraska, n.p. [ 1874 ]
  - Tappan, Henry P. The Progress of Educational Development. [Ann Arbor 1855 ] (Volume III)
  - Tappan, Henry P. Baccalaureate Address Delivered at the Commencement of the University of Michigan, June 27, 1855. [Ann Arbor(?), 1855]
  - Haven, Evastus O. Public Education of Religion. [Ann Arbor 1867 ]
  - Campbell, James V. On the Study of the Law. [Ann Arbor 1859 ]
  - Duffield, D. Bethune. The Lawyer's Oath. [Ann Arbor 1867 ]
  - Winchell, Alexander. The Grand Traverse Region: A Report on the geological and Industrial Resources of the Counties of Antrim, Grand Traverse, Benzie and Leelanaw in the Lower Peninsula of Michigan. [Ann Arbor 1866 ]
  - Winchell, Alexander. Synoptical View of the Geological Succession of Organic Types, [2nd edition. Ann Arbor 1867 ]
  - Stanton, Elizabeth Cady. Address in Favor of Universal Suffrage. [Albany 1867 ]
  - Palmer, Alonzo B. Remarks on Epidemic Cholera. [n.p. undated ]
  - Osgood, Samuel. "New Aspects of the American Mind," Harpers New Monthly Magazine. [ undated ]
  - Anonymous articles. "Characteristics of Genius," "Orion" (poem), "A Week in Sybaris," and "The Destructive Democracy." [ February, 1868 ]
  - Blair, Austin. Governors Message, January 19, 1864. [Lansing 1864 ] (Volume IV)
  - Mickley, Charles E. Majority and Minority Reports of the Special Committee to Whom was Referred the Petition of Solomon L. Bignall, [(House Document No. 23). [Lansing] 1865 ]
  - Address by Honorable Thomas M. Cooley and Poem by D. Bethune Duffield on the dedication of the Law Lecture Hall of Michigan University. Ann Arbor [ 1863 ]
  - Haven, Erastus O. Universities in America: Inaugural Address Delivered in Ann Arbor, Michigan, October 1st, 1863. [Ann Arbor 1863 ]
  - Tappan, Henry P. Review by Reverend Dr. H. P. Tappan of His Connection with the University of Michigan. [Detroit 1864 ]
  - Campbell, Gabriel. War Pictures: A Poem. [Ann Arbor 1865 ]
  - Winchell, Alexander. A Plea for Science. [Cincinnati 1866 ]
  - Address and poem delivered before the chapters of Sigma Phi fraternity. Geneva, New York, 1855
  - Education of the Citizen: Chamber's Papers for the People, [No. 4. undated ]
  - The Songs of Hamilton. [Published by The Class of '67. Utica, New York 1864 ]
  - Songs of the Sigma Phi Alpha of Massachusetts. [n.p. 1861 ]
  - Address to the Masonic Fraternity.
    [title page lacking]
  - Michigan University. Regents Proceedings, 1858- 1863 (Volume V)
  - Michigan University. Regents Proceedings, 1864- 1870 (Volume VI)